So here's something most people don't know, and that is Hamas is actually a creation of Israel.
And people might think that's absolutely nuts, but back in the late 80s,
the leader of the Palestinian Liberation Organization, Yasser Arafat, was consolidating power
between the folks in Gaza and those who lived in the West Bank and occupied East Jerusalem.
So there was a tactic that was decided on that in order to fragment and disrupt that sort of consolidation of power,
that they would create a hardline group knowing that they would fight with the party that was in charge called Fatah,
which is the current party that runs the Palestinian Authority.
So Israel not only created and radicalized this group, but also continued to fund and arm them
so that they would do things that were disruptive and fragment the Palestinian people
in sort of a divide-and-conquer idea.
And much like the U.S. funded the Mujahideen in Afghanistan to fight against the Soviets,
the Israeli government did with Hamas.
And as always tends to happen, the person you radicalize and fund who initially works on your behalf
eventually comes back to bite you in the ass.
And that's exactly what's happened here.
Again, most people don't know that.
And guess who the person was who made the decision to do that?
None other than...